DANIELLE BRYANT

Milwaukee, WI | daniellemonbryant@gmail.com | 954.348.2112 | github.com/daniellembryant | linkedin.com/in/danielle-bryant-mba/

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Software Developer with a passion for project management and web accessibility. Leveraging my strength in debugging with the fine-tuned attention to detail that I honed as a human resources professional, I write clear and readable code with a goal of improving the user experience.

SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, Vue.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PostgreSQL, Git, GitHub, APIs, Pair-Programming, Testing, Object-Oriented Programming, Bootstrap

EDUCATION

Actualize Coding Bootcamp

July 2021 - November 2021

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

- My MS Pal: Personally built a social app designed for people with Multiple Sclerosis (MS) that allows users to read articles about MS, message other users, search and join support groups, and daily motivational quotes. The app was built using Ruby Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, Vue JS and third-party APIs that source relevant content for users.
- **Bootcamp:** Learned fundamentals and best practices in full-stack web development in areas of project architecture, backend, frontend, and how to effectively self-teach new technologies
 - Generated technical requirements and determined the most effective solutions, created wireframes, designed schema, and researched outside resources
 - o Built and tested the backend, incorporating external APIs
 - Created pages and RESTful routes, made web requests to retrieve data, formatted and styled results, incorporated libraries and themes

Nova Southeastern University

May 2016

Master of Business Administration, concentration in HR Management

University of Central Florida

May 2012

Bachelor of Science in Psychology, minor in Marketing

EXPERIENCE

Boys & Girls Clubs of Greater Milwaukee

January 2021 - August 2021

June 2021- August 2021

HR Project Consultant- Contract

- Implemented new HRIS Applicant Tracking System and onboarding platform, which better streamlined the application/onboarding process.
- Configured ATS platform, allowing hiring managers to create job postings and manage applications more efficiently.
- Maintained database for HRIS system by updating employee information and status changes.

HR Generalist

January 2021- June 2021

- Managed all HR related payroll changes and submitted paperwork to the payroll department in a timely manner for bi-weekly processing
- Refined HR's payroll process by implementing internal HR checks that decreased the amount of payroll errors
- Decreased response time for HR requests by establishing a 24 hour turnaround rule, improving department workflow and increasing employee satisfaction
- Processed and approved company wide leave requests and payroll with a focus on timeliness and accuracy

Boys & Girls Clubs of Central Florida

December 2017 - December 2019

HR Generalist

- Optimized background employment screening processes for 14 middle school locations and 8 traditional clubs through clear and consistent communication between supervisors and applicants during the busy summer season
- Developed and supervised new background screening requirements and protocol for Orange County Public Schools
- Supervised hiring and screening protocols for over 200 employees and new hires, ensuring timely fingerprinting and badge completion
- Directed department transition to new system and reviewed eligibility requirements for over 300 employees with a focus on adherence to state and federal laws

Harbour's Edge-Lifespace Communities, Inc.

May 2016 - December 2017

Human Resources Assistant

- Established a cooperative, friendly and safe office environment, encouraging and growing employee engagement
 through the development of strong human resources relationships where previous interactions were low with a poor
 department image
- Trained new hires on company policies and employee-facing HR software
- Delivered cultural training for current and incoming employees, enabling them to provide exceptional customer service to residents